<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | Marcos M. Raimundo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mraimundo/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mraimundo/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/mraimundo/media/icon_hu_ff945c07853dd4a6.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mraimundo/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-objective Learning and Fairness in AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mraimundo/projects/mol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mraimundo/projects/mol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In modern Machine Learning, maximizing accuracy is rarely the only goal. Models must often balance competing requirements such as &lt;strong&gt;fairness&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;interpretability&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;robustness&lt;/strong&gt;. Traditional approaches that combine these metrics into a single loss function often fail to capture the complex landscape of the trade-offs involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project investigates &lt;strong&gt;Multi-objective Learning (MOL)&lt;/strong&gt;: the direct integration of optimization solvers into the neural network training loop. By treating learning as a multi-objective problem, we empower data scientists to explore the Pareto front of possible models before making a final decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-focus&#34;&gt;Research Focus:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algorithmic Fairness:&lt;/strong&gt; A primary application of this research is in &lt;strong&gt;Credit Scoring&lt;/strong&gt;, where we aim to maximize profit/accuracy while minimizing discrimination across demographic groups (e.g., race or gender).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-task Learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Simultaneously training a single neural network to perform multiple tasks (e.g., risk prediction and churn prediction) without one task dominating the gradient updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyperparameter Tuning:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizing bilevel optimization techniques to automatically adjust regularization terms and model architecture during training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Framework:&lt;/strong&gt; Development of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;machinemoo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a high-level library that simplifies the modeling of these complex trade-offs, making multi-objective training accessible to the ML community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
